<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>High-Dimensional Sharpened Dimensionality Reduction</title>
    <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/</link>
    <description>Recent content on High-Dimensional Sharpened Dimensionality Reduction</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of DR and HD-SDR on HAR data with dimensions pre-selected using PCA</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/13/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of DR and HD-SDR on HAR data with dimensions pre-selected using PCA as in Figure 12. Note that the separation of clusters is slightly improved for HD-SDR as compared with DR (although subclusters are visually less separable). We note that nearly all samples in cluster (1) are from the lying movement, cluster (2) mostly includes samples from static postures (standing and sitting), and cluster (3) mostly includes samples from the three dynamic activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of DR and HD-SDR on HAR data with dimensions pre-selected using PCA</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/14/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of DR and HD-SDR using 10 outliers (red crosses) and 5K random points uniformly-distributed in a 20-dimensional hypersphere centered at the origin and with different radii (R=1,2,3,4, and 5). The distances between the outliers and the origin are always 5. Note that t-SNE and UMAP and their sharpened versions fail to preserve the outliers even when the distance between the outliers and the cluster is the largest (row 1). Further note that SRP and SLMDS preserve similar or larger numbers of outliers compared with RP and LMDS, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of DR and HD-SDR on HAR data with dimensions pre-selected using PCA</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/15/</guid>
      <description>Results of DR and SDR with varying k-values for sharpening. The synthetic data set consists of 10K randomly generated samples in 20D. Note that St-SNE shows oversegmented clusters using k=10, while (b) shows a single cluster as in (c) when using k=50.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of neighborhood hit (Qh) for sharpened data and original data of the five different types of synthetic data</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/6/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of neighborhood hit (Qh) for sharpened data and original data of the five different types of synthetic data used in Figure 3. For all synthetic data sets, Qh is always higher for the sharpened data as compared with the original data. We also note that Qh for sharpened data is higher when clusters are more separated (α=0.04 compared with α=0.01).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DR vs. SDR with real-world astronomical data</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/9/</guid>
      <description>We compare DR and HD-SDR (RP, LMDS, t-SNE, and UMAP) for an unlabeled astronomical data set with no ground-truth labels: GALAH DR2 (n=10K with d=10). The projections are color-coded by one of the input values, [Fe/H], so that astronomers can further analyze the data. The learning rate parameter is set to 0.17. Note that in all cases, HD-SDR shows a clearer separation of clusters compared with DR, and SLMDS, St-SNE, and SUMAP exhibit four major clusters with similar distributions of colors within each cluster, while SRP shows three major clusters with one of them having subclusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood hit for five synthetic data sets</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/7/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of neighborhood hit (Qh) for DR and HD-SDR of the five different types of synthetic data used for Figure 3. Note that St-SNE, t-SNE, and SLMDS yield high Qh values near one for (a)&amp;ndash;(c) and (e), which suggests that the corresponding labels of the k-size neighborhoods are well-preserved for HD-SDR. However, HD-SDR for sub-clustered data produces lower Qh compared with DR, as shown in (d), and this can be seen visually in Figure 3(a)&amp;ndash;(d).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood hit for real-world data</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/8/</guid>
      <description>The neighborhood hit (Qh) metric for DR and HD-SDR using labeled real-world data sets with different values of k. We note that Qh is lower for St-SNE than for t-SNE for most values of k in (b)-(d). However for LMDS, which produces a weaker separation of clusters than t-SNE, SLMDS produces a higher value of Qh compared with LMDS for all data sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-DR with PCA using HAR data set</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/12/</guid>
      <description>Proportion of total variance explained by each component when using PCA on Human Activity Recognition (HAR) data. The original data set contains 561 dimensions but can be reduced to 10 dimensions when selecting 80 percent of the variance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tinsely diagrams for SDR results with astronomical data sets</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/10/</guid>
      <description>(a) SLMDS projection of the GALAH DR2 sample, where clusters are visually labeled by one of us (SCT). The labeled clusters in SLMDS help domain experts to further analyze the data as follows: (b) Tinsley diagram for the GALAH DR2 sample, showing the abundance of magnesium as a function of the iron abundance, used to interpret the origin and location of Milky Way stars. This diagram suggests to our domain-expert (SCT) that stars in Class 1 belong to the Milky Way&amp;rsquo;s thin disk&#39;&#39;, while those in Classes 2 and 4 appear to belong to the Milky Way&#39;s metal-rich thick disk&#39;&#39; and metal-poor thick disk&#39;&#39;, respectively, and stars in Class 3 appear to belong to the Milky Way&#39;s stellar halo&#39;&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wall-clock timing of LGC</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/11/</guid>
      <description>(a) Wall-clock timing of LGC, for different number of observations along the x-axis and varying dimensions up to 20D. (b) Wall-clock time measurement of LGC on a 10K (20D) data set, using different learning rates α. (c) Wall-clock time measurements of RP, LMDS, and t-SNE applied to nD LGC data. We note that the wall-clock time of LGC increases with increasing α and depends heavily on the number of dimensions. Moreover, RP and LMDS (landmark ratio=0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results of four neighborhood-based quality metrics for Banknote data</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/5/</guid>
      <description>Results of four neighborhood-based quality metrics for Banknote data: Neighborhood hit (Qh), Trustworthiness (Qt), Continuity (Qc), and Jaccard set distance (Qj). Note that Qhis consistent with results from Figure 3 and best represents the visual cluster separation, whereas Qt, Qc, and Qjsuggest the opposite. Note that Qt, Qc, and Qjdo not consider class label information. More results including Qt, Qc, and Qjfor the five synthetic data sets can be found in the supplemental materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DR vs. HD-SDR for real-world data</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/4/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of DR and HD-SDR using four different real-world data. DR methods are ordered from left to right based on how well clusters are separated. The samples are colored by their ground-truth labels for visual examination purposes. Note that the sharpening method significantly enhances the visual separability of clusters for the first three data sets, except for SUMAP as shown in the eighth column. Additionally, St-SNE and SUMAP exhibit more oversegmentation of clusters than SRP and SLMDS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DR vs. HD-SDR for synthetic data</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/3/</guid>
      <description>Comparison of DR and HD-SDR using five different types of synthetic data. DR methods are ordered from left to right based on how well clusters are separated. The samples are colored by the ground-truth labels of five different clusters for visual examination purposes. The results for SRP and SLMDS have been obtained with α=0.04 and for St-SNE (perplexity=50) and SUMAP with α=0.01. Note that our sharpening method enhances the separation of clusters for DR methods with less ability to separate clusters (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of different hyperparameters using non-Gaussian synthetic data - Lognormal</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/2/</guid>
      <description>Effects of different parameters using 2D non-Gaussian (log-normal, μ=0, and σ=1) data with 10K observations. Note that the effects of the parameters are similar to those of Figure 1. However, LGC with too large values of T and α is prone to outliers (long tails), as shown in (d) and (l), but this problem can be solved by setting a larger value of k.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About </title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/about/</guid>
      <description>All contents from https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/ were submitted to and accepted by the Information Visualization journal. High-dimensional Sharpened Dimensionality Reduction (HD-SDR) High-dimensional Sharpened Dimensionality Reduction (HD-SDR) sharpens the original high-dimensional data before dimensionality reduction to create visually segregrated sample clusters, which is targeted for user-guided labeling.
Setup Code is written in C++ and is available here.
https://github.com/youngjookim/sdr
To get the code running please include the following:
a. Nanoflann header file
b. Eigen 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of different hyperparameters using Gaussian synthetic data</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/1/</guid>
      <description>Effects of parameters used in LGC. 2D Gaussian data with 10K observations and three clusters (a) are used to show the effects of the number of iterations (T) as shown in (a)&amp;ndash;(d), number of nearest neighbors (k) in (e)&amp;ndash;(l), and learning rate (α) in (m)&amp;ndash;(p). Points are color-coded based on their ground-truth labels. The cluster borders become fuzzy when using a too high T, as shown in (d). k and α both contribute to the degree of segmentation of the clusters; without choosing an appropriate α, k may not significantly affect the segmentation, as shown in rows (e)&amp;ndash;(h) and (i)&amp;ndash;(l).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDR results with astronomical data sets</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/experiments/0/</guid>
      <description>All contents from https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/ were submitted to IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON VISUALIZATION AND COMPUTER GRAPHICS.
This video was made based on the results from this figure.
Top-left plot shows the SLMDS projection of the GALAH DR2 sample, where clusters are visually labeled by one of us (SCT). The labeled clusters in SLMDS help domain experts to further analyze the data as follows. The bottom-left plot shows the Tinsley diagram for the GALAH DR2 sample, showing the abundance of magnesium as a function of the iron abundance, used to interpret the origin and location of Milky Way stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental material 1</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/1/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental material 2</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental material 3</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental material 4</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/4/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of GALAH DR2 sample using St-SNE and SUMAP projections (top row), where clusters are visually labeled by one of us (SCT) and the Tinsley diagrams [77] for the GALAH DR2 sample (bottom row), showing the abundance of magnesium and Barium as a function of the iron abundance, used to interpret the origin and location of Milky Way stars. Note that the clusters in SRP are not easily separated, thus excluded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental material 5</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/5/</guid>
      <description>Extended results of the Neighborhood hit (Q_h) for data sets with different k-values and signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) values ranging from 10 to 40, where Gaussian noise has been added. The graphs in the right column show the cluttered area (Q_h is approx. 1) for the graphs in the left column. Overall, note that the Q_h-values are higher for higher SNR values. Further note that the Q_h-values of SDR are always higher than those of the corresponding DR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental material 6</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/6/</guid>
      <description>Results of DR and SDR with varying k-values for sharpening. The synthetic data set consists of 10K randomly generated observations in 20D. Note that (a), (d), and (g) show oversegmented clusters using k=10, while (b), (e), and (h) show a single cluster using k=50 for LGC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplemental material 7</title>
      <link>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://youngjookim.github.io/sdr/supplemental_materials/7/</guid>
      <description>Extended results of speed experiments in logarithmic scale using LMDS, t-SNE, and RP in Figure 11(c). (a) Wall-clock time of LMDS for different numbers of landmark ratios along the x-axis and varying dimensions up to 20D. (b)&amp;ndash;(d) Wall-clock time of LMDS, t-SNE, and RP for data sets with different numbers of dimensions (5D, 10D, 15D, and 20D) and observations ranging from 10K to 50K. The wall-clock timings are an average of 10 trials of randomly generated Gaussian data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
